Dmitrii Pimkin

Senior Java Developer

Sofia, Bulgaria +359 87 615 6861 dpimkin.it@gmail.com github.com/dpimkin linkedin.com/in/dpimkin

SKILLS

- Java
- Spring
- lava EE
- Hibernate
- MyBatis
- R2DBC
- Flyway
- Liquibase
- Jenkins
- gRPC
- Guice
- Maven
- Gradle
- Git
- Docker
- Testcontaines
- Kubernetes
- Helm
- Python
- Ansible
- Selenium
- JavaScript
- AngularJS
- jQuery
- ActiveMQ
- Hazelcast
- PostgreSQL
- Oracle
- MongoDB
- LevelDB
- Berkley DB
- Azure
- Linode

EDUCATION

Moscow Technological Institute Master of Computer Science 2013 — 2015

Saratov State Socio-Economic University Specialist, Statistics 2001 — 2006

ABOUT ME

I am an Oracle certified Senior Java Developer with more than 11 years of experience. I also have a deep understanding of DevOps principles and practices, and have successfully implemented continuous integration and deployment pipelines in my previous roles. I am highly skilled in site reliability engineering and incident investigation, and have a track record of successfully identifying and resolving issues in complex systems. I am a strong problem-solver and enjoy the challenge of tackling difficult technical problems. I'm an excellent communicator both verbally and written.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Java Developer at **Ingram Micro** https://ingrammicrocloud.com 2015 — 2022



- Designed and implemented highly complex features for automation cloud infrastructure product, including attribute model, activity log, firewall, template image, and autoscaling
- Improved reliability and performance of e-commerce billing subsystem through extensive refactoring and optimization
- Developed custom frameworks for remote procedure call, observability, and traceability
- Improved scalability and maintainability
- Created and maintained advanced CI/CD pipelines, enabling seamless and efficient deployment of code changes
- Conducted thorough investigations into production incidents, identifying root causes and implementing solutions to prevent future occurrences
- Dockerized integration and end-to-end tests, improving the reliability and speed of the testing process
- Reworked core functionality of virtual machines provisioning, backing up, resource usage reporting, and security model, resulting in increased efficiency and security
- As a key member of the team, I am responsible for supporting ongoing compliance with PCI PBA and GDPR standards, ensuring that our organization remains compliant and protects sensitive customer data
- Visit production deployments https://home.pl https://telmex.com/web/negocios/servidor-virtual or watch demo https://youtu.be/ifzu0-fq1zq).

Senior Java Developer at YellowDog https://yellowdog.co

2014 - 2015

- Designed and integrated object storage (S3 like) service for cloud service (https://lcfresh.com)
- Collaborated with the QA team to design and implement effective testing strategies for the application
- Wrote and maintained regression tests to ensure the stability and reliability of the application.

Spearheaded integration internal services communication into asynchronous service bus in

Senior Java Developer at **Neoflex Consulting** https://www.neoflex.ru 2013 — 2014

- Probusinessbank
- Automated build and deployment process with Jenkins, Maven, Git
- Developed service registry, scheduling feature for Neoflex Integra product.

Software Java Developer at **Artezio** https://www.artezio.com

2012 - 2013

- Designed and developed Jira Kanban board plugin (https://www.artezio.com/products/jira-board)
- · Enhanced quality system corporate quality management system with real-time data flow
- Implemented features for joint medical system of Russia (EMIAS).

Software Java Developer at **General Electric (DATAC Technologies)** https://www.ge.com 2011 — 2012

- Developed comprehensive integration logic of Honk Kong water supply optimization (WSD)
- Provided performance improvements and internationalization for SCADA RealFlex
- Implemented end-to-end tests with Selenium
- Resolved security issues (i.e. CVE-2008-4322, CVE-2010-4142, CVE-2011-1564).

CERTIFICATES

M101J Dec 2014

MongoDB for Java Developers

1Z0-861

Oracle Certified Professional Java Programmer

Mar 2014

PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES

Sergei Ulitsky (unit manager)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sergey-u-833b0b175

Mikhail Trofimov (account manager)

WhatsApp/Telegram: +7 962 967 7197

Alexander Sedov (team leader)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexsedov

Kristina Berezina (colleague)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kristina-berezina-382626ab

Artem Kuzimin (colleague)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/artem-ratraze-kuzmin

Alexey Shnyakin (colleague)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexey-shnyakin-86a555172